Guide to the Larry Kramer Papers YCAL MSS 722
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Larry Kramer papers
1920-2019
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Kramer, Larry
YCAL MSS 722
1033
217.26 Linear Feet (255 boxes) + 2 rolls, 5 broadsides, 2 record album storage.
The collection documents the career of Larry Kramer as a playwright and author, an advocate for gay rights, and an activist in the fight against AIDS. The collection consists of writings, including manuscripts and drafts of plays, books, screenplays, and articles; AIDS-related material; diaries; correspondence; photographs; printed material; audiovisual material; and other papers. There is also substantial material relating to the founding of Gay Men's Health Crisis and the AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP) in particular, and to the AIDS movement in general.
Conditions Governing Access
The papers are open for research.
Boxes 37, 58, 178-181, 202-205, 228, 260-261 (electronic materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 29-30, 151-152, 184-186, 189, 207, 229, 233, 262-263 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Larry Kramer, 2003-2016.
November 2016 Acquisition: purchased from Larry Kramer on the Donald Windham-Sandy Campbell Collection Endowment Fund, 2016.
July 2019 Acquisition: purchased from Larry Kramer on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2019.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into eight groupings: July 2003 Acquisition (Uncat MSS 520), July 2003 Acquisition (Uncat MSS 785), August 2007 Acquisition (Uncat MSS 975), and October 2008 Acquisition (Uncat MSS 1071), July 2011 Acquisition, February 2016 Acquisition, November 2016 Acquisition, and July 2019 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, writings, correspondence, and material relating to AIDS activism can be found in most, if not all, of the groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
Larry Kramer (1935-2020)
Larry Kramer (1935-2020) was an American playwright, author, public health advocate, and gay rights activist. He graduated from Yale University in 1957 with a B.A. in English, and is the author of several novels, including Faggots (1978), and plays, including The Normal Heart (1985) and Destiny of Me (1992), which explore themes related to gay life and the AIDS crisis. He was an outspoken advocate for gay rights and the fight against AIDS. He was a co-founder of the Gay Men's Health Crisis in the early 1980s, and later founded the AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP) in 1987. Kramer was also the author of several motion picture screenplays, including an adaptation of Women in Love, for which he was nominated for an Academy Award in 1969.
TypeCollection
https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&4b59daa1-9d70-45eb-b40b-ee238d34afdd
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the career of Larry Kramer as a playwright and author, an advocate for gay rights, and an activist in the fight against AIDS. The collection consists of writings, including manuscripts and drafts of plays, books, screenplays, and articles; AIDS-related material; diaries; correspondence; photographs; printed material; audiovisual material; and other papers. There is also substantial material relating to the founding of Gay Men's Health Crisis and the AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP) in particular, and to the AIDS movement in general. Correspondents include Anthony Fauci, Ed Koch, Rodger McFarlane, Joe Mantello, and Ryan Murphy.
AIDS (Disease) -- Patients -- Drama; AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects -- United States; AIDS activists -- United States; American drama -- 20th Century; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Gay activists -- United States; Gay men -- United States -- Drama; Gay men -- United States -- Fiction; Audiocassettes; Born digital; Phonograph records; Photographs; Videocassettes; LGBTQ resource; Fauci, Anthony S., 1940-; Koch, Ed, 1924-2013; Kramer, Larry; Kushner, Tony; McFarlane, Rodger; Mantello, Joe; Murphy, Ryan, 1965-; ACT UP (Organization); Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc
- July 2003 Acquisition, 1968-2002; 345150; 33.38 Linear Feet (36 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  Scope and Contents
  This portion of the collection consists of correspondence, writings, photographs, printed material, audiotapes, videotapes, and other papers by or relating to Larry Kramer.
  Arrangement
  Organized under six headings: AIDS Activism Files; Diaries; Writings; Family Papers; Audiovisual Material; Posters.
  General note
  Former Call Number: Uncat MSS 520
  - AIDS Activism Files, 345181
    Arranged chronologically.
    Files contain a wide range of material documenting the AIDS crisis and relating to Kramer's activism and advocacy in the fight against AIDS, including his work with Gay Men's Health Crisis and AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power. Material includes clippings, photocopies of articles, correspondence, medical reports, publications, conference programs, press material, newsletters, notes, and writings.
    - 1981-1983, 345201; 19 Folders (Box 1)
    - 1983-1985, 345200; 18 Folders (Box 2)
    - 1985-1987, 345199; 20 Folders (Box 3)
    - 1987-1988, 345198; 20 Folders (Box 4)
    - 1988-1989, 345197; 19 Folders (Box 5)
    - 1989-1991, 345196; 17 Folders (Box 6)
    - 1991-1992, 345195; 19 Folders (Box 7)
    - 1992-1993, 345194; 19 Folders (Box 8)
    - 1993-1994, 345193; 6 Folders (Box 9)
    - 1994, 345192; 20 Folders (Box 10)
    - 1995, 345191; 16 Folders (Box 11)
    - 1995-1996, 345190; 14 Folders (Box 12)
    - 1996-1997, 345189; 21 Folders (Box 13)
    - 1997, 345188; 18 Folders (Box 14)
    - 1997-1998, 345187; 20 Folders (Box 15)
    - 1998-1999, 345186; 20 Folders (Box 16)
    - 1999, 345185; 17 Folders (Box 17)
    - 2001, 345184; 21 Folders (Box 18)
    - 2001-2003, 345183; 19 Folders (Box 19)
    - 2002-2003, 345182; 16 Folders (Box 20)
  - Diaries, 345177
    - 1975, 345180; 16 Folders (Box 21)
    - 1992-1999, undated, 345179; 6 Folders (Box 22)
    - Mini diaries, 1977-1989; 345178; 13 Folders (Box 22)
  - Writings, 345166
    - Women in Love (screenplay), 1968-1969; 345176; 9 Folders (Box 23)
    - Women in Love and Other Dramatic Writings, 2002; 345175 (Box 24)
    - "Sissie's Scrapbook", 1973; 345174; 4 Folders (Box 25)
    - "Four Friends", 1973-1974; 345173; 2 Folders (Box 25)
    - The Normal Heart, early documentation, 1974-1983; 345172; 10 Folders (Box 25)
    - Rubin Carter Hurricane, 1989-2000; 345171; 15 Folders (Box 26)
    - Gore Vidal - Larry Kramer: the QW Interview, 1998; 345170 (Box 26)
    - Just Say No: A Play About a Farce, 1999; 345169; 6 Folders (Box 27)
    - Faggots by Larry Kramer, Published version, 345168; (2 copies) (Box 27)
    - Women in Love by D.H. Lawrence, Published version, 345167; (4 copies) (Box 27)
      Includes a first edition and one or more copies annotated by Kramer.
  - Family Papers, 345163
    - "Memories of My Past" by Rea Kramer, 2000; 345165 (Box 27)
    - Scrapbook for Rea Kramer's 80th Birthday, 1979; 345164 (Box 28)
  - Audiovisual Material, 345160
    Conditions Governing Access
    Boxes 29-30 (Audiocassettes and videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Audiocassettes, 1983-1998; 345162; (20 tapes)
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - ENNO, 1982 September 27; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:30:54 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program starts and ends abruptly. Audio distortion, hum and hiss are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889440)
        Audiovisual material: Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - J. Snuster / Bruce Anderson, 1988 January 27, March 3; 1 Audiocassettes; 01:31:16 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Dropouts in the audio are present. Overlapping content is present. The program was recorded at a very high level at times. Audio is unbalanced at times. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889457)
      - "Ideas" on AIDS - CBC Radio, 1988 June 6; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:56:19 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Dropouts in the audio are present. An echo can be heard at times. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889465)
      - Project Inform, Update Town Meeting, "Nutrition", 1993 January 27; 1 Audiocassettes; 02:04:26 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); Static and dropouts in the audio are present. The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. The program was recorded at a very high level. Crosstalk is present. There is an echo in the audio at times. High amounts of hum are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889473)
      - Project Inform update: special report from the Immune Restoration Think Tank 2, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; 02:02:19 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Dropouts in the audio are present. The program was recorded at a very high level at times. Audio is unbalanced for the first hour of the program. High amounts of hum are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889481)
      - Gary Noble, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; 01:03:23 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program starts and ends abruptly. Audio distortion, hum and hiss are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889499)
      - A. Bauer, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:45:20 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program starts and ends abruptly. Audio distortion, hum and hiss are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889507)
      - Larry Kramer, closing remarks at [Key West] Literary Seminar, San Carlos, Key West, FL, 1997 January 12; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:09:28 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program starts and ends abruptly. Audio distortion, hum and hiss are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889515)
      - New Haven Gay Town Meeting, WQUN AM, 1997 October 8; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:02:13 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Dropouts in the audio are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889523)
      - Larry Kramer on WNYC (NPR), 1997 June 19; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:25:58 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. The program, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Dropouts and static in the program are present. High frequency noise can be heard. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889531)
        Annotation on the audicassette reads: "On the Line" hosted by Brian Lehver; subject "Sex + Sensibility" from The Advocate.
      - Dr. Robert Windom, 1987 May 19; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:17:16 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Static and dropouts in the audio are present. The program is recorded at a very low level. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889549)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; This tape is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889556)
      - AIDS, "Awaken World", 1987; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:14:52 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); Static and dropouts are present in the audio. The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889564)
      - "The AIDS Lament", 1987; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:13:50 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Static and dropouts in the audio are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889572)
      - Advocacy and Literature, Dawidoff, Gomez, Kramer, Schulman, White, The Key West Literary Seminar - Tape 4, Part 1, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:59:21 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); High background noise and static are present. Dropouts in the audio are present. The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889580)
      - Advocacy and Literature, Dawidoff, Gomez, Kramer, Schulman, White, The Key West Literary Seminar - Tape 4, Part 2, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:46:59 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); High background noise is present. The program is distorted at times. Dropouts in the audio can be heard. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889598)
      - AIDS and Contemporary Theatre, A Conversation, Larry Kramer, Tony Kushner & Frank Rich, The Key West Literary Seminar - Tape 6, Part 1, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; 01:15:33 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); High background noise and dropouts in the audio are present. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. The program is distorted at times. Static can be heard. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889606)
      - AIDS and Contemporary Theatre, A Conversation, Larry Kramer, Tony Kushner & Frank Rich, The Key West Literary Seminar - Tape 6, Part 2, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:33:31 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. High background noise is present. Dropouts are present in the program. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889614)
      - "Emprise", Tape 1, undated; 1 Audiocassettes; 01:08:09 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. High background noise and dropouts can be heard. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889622)
      - "The Emprise Opportunity", 1994; 1 Audiocassettes; 00:17:32 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The program is distorted at times. Audio, at times, sounds hollow or unclear. Static and dropouts in the audio are present. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002104889630)
    - Videocassettes
      - "Shatzi is Dying: a video by Jean Carlomusto", 2000; YCALMSS722_0040; 345161; 1 Videocassettes (VHS); 00:57:10 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm) (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102338291)
      - Elton John: Live by Request 2:00, undated; YCALMSS722_0041; 658198; 1 Videocassettes (VHS); 02:03:00 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The audio is very low on the tape. (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102338309)
        There is a note attached from a Jed Mattes notepad. It reads: Larry dear - you rock!
      - Larry Kramer on NH Gay Town Meeting, 11pm news WTNH-TV 8, 1997 October 8; YCALMSS722_0042; 658210; 1 Videocassettes (VHS); 00:05:44 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The recording is in poor quality. Both the video and the audio are noisy. (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102338317)
        A note with the tape reads: Larry-As promised-Michael
      - "Condoms Don't Stop AIDS: Get the Facts that the Government Isn't Telling You", undated; YCALMSS722_0043; 658215; 1 Videocassettes (VHS); 02:41:44 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); The condition of the video is extremely poor. Audio is also very low and there is a hiss throughout the tape. (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102338325)
      - New York Diary, a film by Jay Corcoran, 2002; YCALMSS722_0044; 658220; 1 Videocassettes (VHS); 00:12:15 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm) (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102338333)
      - Elton John: Live by Request 2:00 (duplicate copy?), undated; YCALMSS722_0045; 658229; 1 Videocassettes (VHS); 02:00:52 Duration (HH:MM:SS.mmm); This is a better copy of the Elton John concert special. (Box 30, Item barcode 39002102338341)
  - Visual Material, 345158
    - "Larry Kramer's Secret," poster, 1995; 345159 (Box 31 (Broadside))
  - Previously restricted material, 345151
    - Drafts and scripts of "The American People", 2002-2003; 345157; 0 See Container Summary 17 folders (Box 32)
    - Drafts of "The American People", undated; 345156; 0 See Container Summary 17 folders (Box 33)
    - Drafts of "The American People", undated; 345155; 0 See Container Summary 17 folders (Box 34)
    - Drafts of "The American People", undated; 345154; 15 Folders (Box 35)
    - Drafts of "The American People", undated; 345153; 0 See Container Summary 13 folders (Box 36)
    - Credit and bank statements, 0 See Container Summary 6 folders (Box 235)
  - Computer files
    Box 37: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Disk # 2003.ycal.0728.0001
    Box 235: Restricted material. Contact the appropriate curator for further information.
    - Compaq computer, 345152 (Box 37)
      Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Disk # 2003.ycal.0728.0001
- July 2003 Acquisition, 1997-2001; 345135; 0.46 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  This portion of the collection consists of correspondence, bookjackets and printed material, including Lambda book report, which were transferred back to the manuscript collection from the Printed Acquisitions unit of the Beinecke Library.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 785
  - "Keith" to Larry Kramer, letter, 1989 February 10; 345149 (Box 38)
  - Keith Condon to Larry Kramer, letter, 2001 April 17; 345148 (Box 38)
  - William Schwalbe business card, annotated, 345147 (Box 38)
  - Time Out: New York, 2000 August; 345146 (Box 38)
  - Atlantic Monthly Press, Winter, 2001; 345145 (Box 38)
  - The Harvard Gay and Lesbian Review, Spring, 1997; 345144 (Box 38)
  - The Journal of NIH Research, 1993 July; 345143 (Box 38)
  - Lambda Book Report, 2000 July/August; 345142 (Box 38)
  - POZ, 1998 August; 345141 (Box 38)
  - "Larry Kramer Two Plays - The Normal Heart and The Destiny of Me", book covers, 345140 (Box 38)
  - "Larry Kramer - Faggots", book cover, 345139 (Box 38)
  - The New Republic, 1998 April; 345138 (Box 38)
  - The Village Voice, 1998 April; 345137 (Box 39)
  - L G N Y: the Newspaper for Lesbian and Gay New York, 1997 July 6; 345136 (Box 39)
- August 2007 Acquisition, 1983-2005; 345093; 17.04 Linear Feet (19 boxes)
  This portion of the collection consists of correspondence, writings, Gay Men's Health Crisis files, notebooks, photographs, audio and visual recordings and other papers, which originated from Kramer's home in Connecticut.
  Organized into three series: I. Correspondence. II. Gay Men's Health Crisis. III. Other Papers.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 975
  TypeCollection
  https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&dfd754ca-3fc5-409e-91e7-405a4c4ef96b
  - Correspondence, 345127
    Files consist largely of incoming and outgoing correspondence and email printouts, as well as assorted other papers.
    Files are arranged in very rough chronological order. When material arrived, it was loose and grouped into boxes by year, beginning with the year 2000 and ending with the year 2007. The material within each box was found to span a broader range of dates, and so date ranges are supplied in the list below to better reflect the actual contents.
    - 2000-2001, 345134; 18 Folders (Box 40)
    - (includes earlier material from 1983-2001), 2001-2004; 345133; 15 Folders (Box 41)
    - (includes earlier material from 1999-2003), 2004; 345132; 17 Folders (Box 42)
    - 2004, 345131; 15 Folders (Box 43)
    - (includes earlier material from 2003), 2004-2005; 345130; 13 Folders (Box 44)
    - (includes earlier material from 2004), 2005-2007; 345129; 18 Folders (Box 45)
    - 2007, 345128; 4 Folders (Box 46)
  - Gay Men's Health Crisis, 345115
    - Correspondence, 1983-1985; 345126; 2 Folders (Box 47)
    - Funding Proposal, undated; 345125 (Box 47)
    - Publications, undated; 345124; 2 Folders (Box 47)
    - Files, undated; 345123; 5 Folders (Box 47)
    - ACT UP (early), circa 1983; 345122 (Box 47)
    - Files, undated; 345121; 3 Folders (Box 47)
    - The Madison Project, circa 1993; 345120; 2 Folders (Box 47)
    - The Madison Project, undated; 345119 (Box 47)
    - Notebook - The Madison Project, circa 1993; 345118 (Box 47)
    - Notebook - The Madison Project, circa 1993; 345117; 2 Folders (Box 48)
    - New York Blood Center, circa 1985; 345116; 3 Folders (Box 48)
  - Other Papers, 345105
    - Lake Watch, 1996-1999; 345114; 3 Folders (Box 48)
    - AIDS Clinical Research, 1996-1997; 345113 (Box 48)
    - Letters to Thomas Stoddard, 1990; 345112 (Box 48)
    - Photographs - The Destiny of Me, undated; 345111 (Box 48)
    - "The Lady and the Hard Hat", 1973; 345110 (Box 48)
    - The Normal Heart, screenplay, 1986; 345109 (Box 48)
    - The Normal Heart, screenplay, 1994; 345108 (Box 48)
    - Magazines and various materials, 345107 (Box 48)
    - David Scott Morgan photograph, circa 1990; 345106 (Box 48)
    - Medical and health related files, 345104; 18 Folders (Box 49)
    - Tax returns, 1998-2007; 345103; 21 Folders (Box 50)
    - "The American People" drafts, undated; 345102; 0 See Container Summary 16 folders (Box 51)
    - "The American People" drafts, undated; 345101; 0 See Container Summary 22 folders (Box 52)
    - "The American People" drafts, undated; 345100; 0 See Container Summary 18 folders (Box 53)
    - "The American People" drafts, undated; 345099; 0 See Container Summary 22 folders (Box 54)
    - "The American People" drafts, undated; 345098; 0 See Container Summary 24 folders (Box 55)
    - "The American People" drafts, undated; 345097; 0 See Container Summary 29 folders (Box 56)
    - "The American People" drafts, undated; 345096; 0 See Container Summary 21 folders (Box 57)
    - "Faggots" drafts, 1975 (Box 236)
    - "Faggots" bits and pieces for "The American People", undated (Box 236)
    - Writings and notes, undated (Box 236)
    - Writings and notes, circa 1980 (Box 236)
    - "Whore House" and other writings, undated (Box 236)
    - "The American People" drafts, 2005; 0 See Container Summary 2 folders (Box 236)
    - Computer media, 345095
      Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information: Disk #2007.ycal.9946.001-003.
      https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&a536f151-f606-43a0-b35d-04446be4676c
      - LK 1, 2007-ycal-9946-0001; 1 3.5_floppy_disks (Box 58)
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&642e8c60-c26f-489f-b080-e08aecabe054
      - LK 2, 2007-ycal-9946-0002; 1 3.5_floppy_disks (Box 58)
        https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&28764dd6-fbb5-43da-abde-df65de806cc2
      - LK 3, 2007-ycal-9946-0003; 1 3.5_floppy_disks (Box 58)
        https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&8f31d4c4-7fa0-4f0b-ae81-0b5a86a4c236
- October 2008 Acquisition, circa 1916-2008; 344633; 100.63 Linear Feet (117 boxes) + 2 broadside folders, 8 rolls, 2 record albums
  Organized into six series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Writing Files. IV. Professional Papers and Research Material. V. Personal and Other Papers. VI. Audiovisual Material.
  These series represent broad groupings. Material within one series overlaps with material found in other series.